utas.edu.au 2019-12-21

# Privacy at the University of Tasmania - University of Tasmania | University of Tasmania

The University of Tasmania (“the University”, “we”) is committed to your privacy. Privacy matters to us and we know it matters to you. The University is committed to protecting your privacy, keeping your information safe and ensuring the security of your information and data.

The information contained on this website and in the statements below explains how the University collects, uses, and discloses your personal information and your rights in relation to your privacy.

The University is committed to ensuring it complies with its legislative obligations under the _Personal Information Protection Act 2004_ (Tas) (“PIP Act”), the _Privacy Act 1988_ (Cth) when the University has obligations and/or contractual obligations to the Commonwealth Government; and the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) when the University processes the personal data of data subjects in the European economic area. To read further on this, please see the University’s Privacy Policy contained below.

#### What is personal information?

Personal Information is any information where your identity is reasonably ascertainable. This definition includes a broad range of information such as your name, email address, photo, telephone number, video or comments from an interview and often depends on the context and circumstances. If you are in the European Economic Zone, this will also include all personal data defined in the GDPR.

#### How do we keep and store your information?

The University is committed to keeping your information secure in accordance with the privacy legislation and our Privacy Policy. As custodians of your information, the University uses a combination of technical solutions, security and access controls, and internal processes to help us protect your information and our network from unauthorised access, misuse and unintentional disclosure.

We hold information in electronic and paper-based records management systems or appropriate business systems and repositories. We take all reasonable steps to ensure that the information we hold is protected from misuse, loss, unauthorised access or disclosure. We will retain your personal information in accordance with our [Records Management Policy, Procedure and Guidelines](https://www.utas.edu.au/policy/by-category#162003).

Your information will also be held in externally hosted applications. Some of these applications are located outside of Tasmania, and others are also hosted outside of Australia. As a result, your information will be transferred outside of Tasmania (but within Australia) or outside of Australia. The University will ensure that any organisation which hosts or keeps your information for us will be required to maintain the same privacy safeguards which the University maintains.

#### How can you access or correct your information?

The University takes reasonable steps to ensure that the information we collect, use and disclose is accurate, complete and up to date. To ensure the quality and accuracy of the information that we hold, we expect you to update your information when your details change.

To access the information the University holds about you, please contact the following relevant contact:

In some circumstances, information may not be able to be accessed or disclosed unless it is required under the _Right to Information Act 2009_ (Tas). Please refer to the [University’s Right to Information process](https://www.utas.edu.au/legal-services/right-to-information) for further details.

## University Privacy Policy

For extensive information on how the University manages your information, download the [University’s Privacy Policy (PDF 155KB)](https://www.utas.edu.au/__data/assets/pdf_file/0014/1211423/Privacy-Policy-190321.pdf).

#### Student Privacy Statement

The purpose for this statement is to inform you about the way in which the University uses and manages your information.

#### What information do we collect?

#### Personal Information

The University collects personal information from you for a number of purposes, which are explained in further detail below. The personal information is any information which identifies you and includes:

  * Your name, address and other details about you and this may be included in a written form;
  * Photographs, images, video or audio footage, CCTV footage of you.

#### Sensitive Information

The University will not collect Sensitive information (as defined in the PIP Act) such as religious, political or sexual preference unless:

  * You consent to the collection; or
  * The collection of the information is required or authorised by or under Australian law.

#### Health Information

The University may be required to collect health information from you to assist us to provide you services you need which may be required to complete your studies. The health information may include:

  * Any mental or physical disabilities or conditions you have which may affect your ability to study;
  * Any mental or physical disabilities or conditions you have which may affect your ability to conduct assessments or conduct examinations.

#### Why do we collect the information?

On lodgement of your application, the primary purpose for collecting the information is to assess your application to study at the University. If your application is successful, purposes for which we will use your information include: to deliver a course of study, assess your eligibility for scholarships, bursaries, prizes and other awards, to administer your enrolment, progression, and graduation in accordance with our policies, procedures and processes.  

We also collect your information for related purposes such as:

  * To include you in activities, services and events incidental to study and made available to students at the University;
  * To inform you about professional opportunities, international opportunities and experiences, and future learning programs.
  * To comply with the _Higher Education Support Act 2003_ (Cth), the _Education Services for Overseas Students Act 2000_ (Cth), and the National Code of Practice for Registration Authorities and Providers of Education and Training to Overseas Students 2018.

The University collects information to provide you with education and education support services in all our courses and offerings.

#### How do we collect the information?

The University will collect your information directly from you during the enrolment process and throughout your time as a student at the University. We will collect this information from you directly in person, electronically, in hard copy, by telephone or in a face to face meeting.

After your enrolment, when you are using the University websites or requesting or applying for a University service, you may be asked to provide information about yourself such as your student number, name, contact details or other personal information. You may be required to complete information in an online form.

While we usually collect personal information from you directly, there may be circumstances where information may be provided on your behalf, such as from third parties where this would be reasonably expected or with your consent. This may include to verify your education history, financial position and residency status.

We will only collect information from other sources with your consent or in accordance with the law.

#### How do we use your information

We will only use your information:

  * For the purposes for which it was collected
  * For a directly related purpose
  * When we have the appropriate consent to do so, or
  * As otherwise required, permitted or authorised by law such as for reporting purposes to the Commonwealth, State Departments and other statutory bodies.

Your information may be de-identified and used for survey data. You will not be identified through this process and we will use best endeavours to ensure that it is not re-identifiable.

If there has been an incident and it has been reported, and where information is sensitive, the University may anonymise, collate and analyse this data and information to improve academic and welfare support.

The following is a non-exhaustive list of the types of uses of your information that you should expect:

#### Admission and academic administration

  1. To undertake selection into University courses and offerings;
  2. To enrol and re-enrol you into courses, units and offerings;
  3. To determine eligibility for scholarships, bursaries, prizes and other awards;
  4. To communicate with you about your courses, activities, services, and opportunities such as study abroad, work integrated learning, student wellbeing, residential services and parking as examples;
  5. To assess your academic work and academic progress;
  6. For timetabling services;
  7. To operate externally hosted applications as part of providing education and candidature services to you such as google, Microsoft, our Learning Management System, MyLo, online courses and pre-enrolment testing providers, where appropriate;
  8. For eligibility for FEE-HELP, HECS-HELP, VET FEE-HELP, OS-HELP, OR VET Student Loans to assess your entitlement to Commonwealth assistance and allocation of your Commonwealth Higher Education Student Support Number (CHESSN);
  9. For the purposes of other institutions (whether located in Australia or overseas) who are involved in the delivery of your course of study;
  10. For assessing your eligibility for circumstances such as remission, refunds, or for sitting exams;
  11. For plagiarism detection, such as using the Turnitin plagiarism detection service;
  12. To process your graduation, including publishing your name, date of graduation, and award obtained publicly;
  13. To process changes to your status at the University including exclusion and withdrawal.
  14. Convocation programmes, which include the name and award of each graduate at that ceremony are a public record of the University.

#### Communication and Information Services

  1. To provide you with access to and support from
    1. Information Technology Services;
    2. Library services and third-party online learning resources
  2. To use and for the University to analyse student information of systems such as MyLo and the University network to enable analytics and to identify and contact students who may need additional support and services;
  3. To make you aware of University news and events;
  4. To invite you to participate in surveys or research;
  5. To make you aware of additional and further opportunities for further study.

#### Student Safety and Wellbeing Support

  1. To provide you with access to and support from University safety and wellbeing services, including:
    1. Student services;
    2. Disability support;
    3. Equity and diversity;
    4. Tutoring programs including programs such as PASS;
    5. Personal counselling;
    6. Health services;
    7. Recreational services;
    8. Career counselling
    9. Safe community services;
    10. Insurance and travel services;
  2. To communicate with you and your nominated contact in the event of an emergency or risk to safety and wellbeing.

#### Security and complaints

  1. To manage, investigate and report incidents relating to inappropriate behaviour general misconduct, or breaches to academic or research integrity;
  2. To manage and investigate complaints and appeals.

#### Planning and quality assurance

  1. To undertake audit, planning and statistical analysis, benchmarking, quality assurance activities, continuous quality improvement;
  2. For research (which is for internal use and for statutory reporting).

#### Alumni

  1. To engage and connect with you within the University’s alumni network and associated services such as inclusion on the Alumni and Advancement Office database to seek your support in the future.

#### Who do we disclose your information to?

The University may disclose your information, only to the extent necessary, to:

  * our contracted services providers, such as mailing houses, logistics, banks, IT providers, lawyers, consultants and other professional advisors;
  * our onshore and offshore partners where necessary for the enrolment and administration of study you undertake hosted by them, including professional placements and courses provided through other educational institutions;
  * professional registration bodies;
  * our student associations;
  * Scholarship selection committee members both inside and outside of University;
  * Scholarship providers;
  * in the event of a critical incident or emergency, police, medical and other emergency services personnel, your nominated emergency contact or other person necessary to respond to the situation;
  * third parties who are contracted to administer surveys to students and graduates on behalf of the University;
  * external research funding bodies and partners, to fulfil research reporting requirements;
  * government bodies such as Centrelink, the Australian Taxation Office, the Department of Home Affairs, the State and Federal Department of Education and Training, and the Department of Immigration and Border Protection; and
  * as otherwise required by law.

The University may publish your academic results by reference to your Student Identification Number. It is your responsibility to keep your Student Identification Number private and not disclose it to any other person except as authorised by our staff or procedures.

#### How can you access the information the University holds about you?

You can request access to the information we hold about you by contacting the UConnect Team by emailing [U.Connect@utas.edu.au](mailto:U.Connect@utas.edu.au) or calling 1300 361 928.

#### Staff Privacy Statement

The purpose for this statement is to inform you about the way in which the University uses and manages your information.

#### What information do we collect?

#### Personal Information

The University collects personal information from you for a number of purposes, which are explained in further detail below. The personal information is any information which identifies you and includes:

  * Your name, address and other details about you and this may be included in a written form;
  * Your tax file number, banking and superannuation details;
  * Employment history and referee reports;
  * Pre-employment health assessments;
  * Qualifications and licences;
  * Work permits and visa details;
  * Security/background checks, identity checks and police checks;
  * Psychometric assessments;
  * Information publicly available on social media and professional networking websites;
  * Details of other commitments such as directorships or other work; and
  * Photographs, images, video or audio footage, CCTV footage of you.

#### Sensitive Information

The University will not collect Sensitive information (as defined in the PIP Act) such as religious, political or sexual preference unless:

  * You consent to the collection; or
  * The collection of the information is required or authorised by or under Australian law.

#### Health Information

The University may be required to collect health information from you when you commence work as part of the University’s work, health and safety monitoring. You will be asked questions regarding your medical and vaccination history to identify any areas where there could be a health or hazard risk. This information will be assessed and stored in your employee record.

#### Information from third parties

In the recruitment process, you might also need to provide personal information about other individuals to the University such as your referee contact details. We rely on you to ask those individuals for their consent for you to pass on their information to us.

#### Why do we collect the information?

The primary purpose for collecting your information is to maintain your employee record and to administer your employment, salary, and superannuation.

We also collect your information for related purposes such as:

  * To include you in activities, services and events which are incidental to your employment.

#### How do we collect the information?

The University will collect your information from you during your application and appointment as well as throughout your time as an employee of the University. We will collect this information from you directly in person, electronically, in hard copy, by telephone, or in a face to face meeting.

After your appointment, when you are using the University websites or requesting or applying for a University service, you may be asked to provide information about yourself such as your staff number, name, contact details or other personal information. You may be required to complete information in an online form.

While we usually collect personal information from you directly, there may be circumstances where information may be provided on your behalf, such as from third parties where this would be reasonably expected or with your consent. This may include to verify your education history, financial position and residency status.

We will only collect information from other sources with your consent or in accordance with the law.

#### How do we use your information

We will only use your personal information:

  * For the purposes for which it was collected
  * For a directly related purpose
  * When we have the appropriate consent to do so, or
  * As otherwise required, permitted or authorised by law.

The University may also collect your information through online recruitment services, and those are managed by third parties.

The University may also use your information for other HR related purposes such as for data analysis, quality assurance, and will de-identify your data and use it to report on workforce data. The University will use your information to fulfil our legislative reporting requirements.

The following is a non-exhaustive list of the types of uses of your information that you should expect:

#### Appointment and employment

  1. To determine your suitability for employment with the University throughout our recruitment process;
  2. To verify your identity with third parties, contact referees and conduct employment-related checks;
  3. To determine and process your pay and other entitlements such as superannuation and leave;
  4. To attend to day to day administrative matters.

#### Communication and Information Services

  1. To correspond with you;
  2. To inform you about the range of facilities and services available to you;
  3. For the provision of services such as security, facilities and parking;
  4. To provide you with access to and support from
    1. Information Technology Services;
    2. Library services and third-party online learning resources such as LinkedIn Learning;
  5. To use and for the University to analyse staff information of systems such as MyLo and the University network to enable analytics and to identify and contact staff who may need additional support;
  6. To make you aware of University news and events;
  7. To inform you of employment opportunities with the University;
  8. To invite you to participate in surveys or research.

#### Welfare Support

  1. To provide you with access to and support from University services, including:
    1. Disability support;
    2. Equity and diversity;
    3. Personal counselling;
    4. Health services;
    5. Recreational services;
    6. Career counselling
    7. Safer communities services;
    8. Insurance and travel services;
  2. To communicate with you and your nominated contact in the event of an emergency.

#### Planning and quality assurance

  1. To undertake audit, planning and statistical analysis, benchmarking, quality assurance activities, continuous quality improvement;
  2. For research (which is for internal use and for statutory reporting)

#### Who do we disclose your information to?

The University may disclose your information, only to the extent necessary, to:

  * our contracted services providers, such as mailing houses, logistics, banks, IT providers, lawyers, consultants and other professional advisors;
  * in the event of a critical incident or emergency, police, medical and other emergency services personnel, your nominated emergency contact or other person necessary to respond to the situation;
  * external research funding bodies and partners, to fulfil research reporting requirements;
  * government bodies such as Centrelink, the Australian Taxation Office, the Department of Home Affairs, the State and Federal Department of Education and Training, the Workplace Gender Equality Agency, and the Department of Immigration and Border Protection; and
  * as otherwise required by law.

#### How can you access the information the University holds about you?

You can request access to the information we hold about you by contacting Human Resources by emailing [Human.Resources@utas.edu.au](mailto:Human.Resources@utas.edu.au)

## General – Privacy Statements

The University collects, uses and discloses information from you in several of its operations and systems. Those are outlined below:

#### Web

Your information is collected through use of the University’s websites and online services.

Please note that the University is not responsible for the personal information you provide through your use of non-university websites while using the University’s web and online resources.

#### How is information collected?

#### Web forms

The University may require you to enter your information into a web form. We will use your information as outlined in these statements.

#### Blogs, surveys and online teaching

The University may require you to enter your information through authenticated websites through blogs, surveys and online teaching. We will use your information as outlined in these statements. It is important to be aware that your information and identity may become viewable to other users on online teaching resources such as through MyLo, online discussion boards and online blogs.

#### Automated collection of information

When you visit a University of Tasmania website, the web server automatically records your visit and logs the following information:

  1. The browser’s internet address;
  2. The visitor’s domain name;
  3. The date and time of the visit;
  4. The pages accessed and documents downloaded;
  5. The previous site visited;
  6. The type of browser used;

The University’s websites also use first-party cookie-based technologies such as Google Analytics to autonomously record statistics and information about:

  1. The Internet Protocol (IP) address number that is assigned by the visitor’s Internet Service Provider (ISP);
  2. The name of the ISP;
  3. The visitor’s connection speed;
  4. The geographical region (city, state, country);
  5. The date and time of the visit;
  6. The pages accessed and documents downloaded;
  7. The referral site and page visited;
  8. The type and version of browser used;

Additional information collected may include usernames (account names), however this is only for sites that use an HTTP authentication.

#### Cookies

Further to the above, the University may collect information through cookies to be used for marketing, audit, statistical and security purposes as well as to provide and improve its website services.

In some instances, the University may provide de-identified data to third parties on a project basis for the purposes of developing a better website and improved user experience based on data analysis. Note that if you choose to block the installation of cookies, you may not be able to access some of the University’s pages without re-authenticating on each site.

#### Social media

The University may use social media tracking to track your activity from the University’s social media sites through use of cookies, analytics software and double click tracking.

#### Marketing and Events 

Your information may be collected and used by the University through its marketing activities and at University events.

#### Marketing

The University may collect your information from you personally through online competitions, forms we ask you to fill out, and when you make an enquiry with the University as some examples.

Through this collection, the University may send you information about our offerings, events and follow up on any questions you may have asked us.

You may see advertisements of our services and course offerings on third party websites including social media websites like Facebook and Instagram. Where you see an advertisement on a third party website or social media platform, this may be because we engaged the third party or social media platform to show this advertisement to you or people who have similar attributes to you.

#### Events

The University may collect your information at our events. This may include through the University taking videos of our events, asking you to fill out a form, or even through your registration to an event. The University may use your information to contact you and let you know about what we are doing and instances where you might be interested in our activities.

#### Market research

The University may collect and use your information for market research purposes collected through any of our marketing and events activities. This may also include using University systems.

The University may use this information for several purposes. A non-exhaustive list includes:

  1. Contacting you about our offerings;
  2. Linking your information with information we may have about you already;
  3. Direct marketing purposes;
  4. Market research so we can understand how we can do better.

#### Scholarships, Bursaries, Prizes and other awards

Your information may be collected, stored and used by the University for the purpose of assessing, allocating and administering scholarships, bursaries, prizes and other awards.

The personal information supplied in your application may also be viewed by:

  1. Scholarship selection committee members both internal and external to the University) to facilitate the assessment, selection, allocation and ongoing eligibility of scholarships, bursaries, prizes and awards;
  2. Scholarship providers; and
  3. The State Government and the Commonwealth.

The University of Tasmania may also use your information to:

  4. Contact you regarding potential scholarship, bursary, prize and other award opportunities; and
  5. Invite you to participate in surveys and research.

#### Alumni

As a graduate of the University, your information will be contained in the University’s alumni database. We may use your information to:

  1. Provide you with services and enable you to participate in activities directed at University alumni;
  2. Inform you about opportunities for continuing education;
  3. Contact you for marketing and fundraising initiatives;
  4. Assist us with planning and quality assurance;
  5. Invite you to participate in surveys and research.

#### Are you in the European Union?

As provided for in the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), you have the right:

  * to access your data; to correct or rectify your data;
  * to delete your data subject to applicable law;
  * to have your data processed only in accordance with applicable law;
  * to have copies of your data to be moved to another controller;
  * to object to our processing your data otherwise than in accordance with the law; and
  * to withdraw any consent to our processing your data at any time.

Please contact our Data Protection Officer to exercise these rights.

Email:   

Mail:   
Privacy Officer and Data Protection Officer   
University of Tasmania   
Private Bag 42   
Hobart TAS 7000

#### How can you make a complaint?

If you feel that the University has not acted in accordance with the University’s Privacy Policy or the Privacy Statements below, you may make a complaint in writing or by email to the General Counsel, who is also the University’s Privacy Officer and Data Protection Officer.

Email:   

Mail:   
Privacy Officer and Data Protection Officer   
University of Tasmania   
Private Bag 42   
Hobart TAS 7000

Please also refer to the University’s full [complaints procedure](https://secure.utas.edu.au/legal-services-secure/privacy/complaints).

#### Unsubscribe

If you’d like to unsubscribe from the University’s marketing emails or mailing lists, please contact marketing on [Marketing.Office@utas.edu.au](mailto:Marketing.Office@utas.edu.au)
